Farrel Company Records 1989.0053
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series IV: General Accounts, 1845-1981
  - Cash receipts and disbursements, 1977 January - 1977 December (Box 34:, Folder 766)
  - Cash receipts and disbursements, 1978 January - 1978 December (Box 34:, Folder 767)
  - Cash receipts and disbursements, 1979 January - 1979 December (Box 34:, Folder 768)
  - Cash receipts and disbursements, 1980 January - 1980 December (Box 34:, Folder 769)
  - Cash receipts and disbursements, 1981 January - 1981 June (Box 34:, Folder 770)
  - Daybook - machine shop, 1848-1849 (Box 34:, Folder 771)
  - Extra compensation, 1928-1930 (Box 34:, Folder 772)
  - Farmer's Bank account, 1852-1853 (Box 34:, Folder 773)
  - Farmer's Bank account, 1857 (Box 34:, Folder 774)
  - General ledger, 1893-1896 (Box 34:, Folder 775)
  - General ledger, 1896-1898 (Box 34:, Folder 776)
  - General ledger, 1898-1900 (Box 34:, Folder 777)
  - Income account of Franklin Farrel, 1889-1892 (Box 34:, Folder 778)
  - Index
    - Ledger C, 1850 (Box 34:, Folder 779)
    - Ledger G (Box 34:, Folder 780)
    - Ledger H (Box 34:, Folder 781)
    - Ledger I (Box 34:, Folder 782)
    - Ledger J, 1897-1898 (Box 34:, Folder 783)
    - Ledger K, 1899-1900 (Box 34:, Folder 784)
  - Ledger sheets, 1845-1848 (Box 34:, Folder 785)
  - Ledger sheets, 1849-1857 (Box 34:, Folder 786)
  - Receipts and invoices, 1848-1858 (Box 34:, Folder 787)
  - Receipts and invoices, 1863-1869 (Box 34:, Folder 788)
  - Receipts and invoices, 1870-1873 (Box 34:, Folder 789)
  - Receipts and invoices, 1880-1886 (Box 34:, Folder 790)
  - Receipts and invoices, 1897-1915 (Box 34:, Folder 791)
  - Record of iron, coal, wood and other expenses, 1858 (Box 34:, Folder 792)
  - Bills received, 1925-1929 (Box 35:, Folder 793)
  - General ledger, 1920 (Box 35:, Folder 794)
  - General ledger, 1927-1929 (Box 35:, Folder 795-799)
  - Trial balance record, 1947 (Box 35:, Folder 800)
  - Ledgers
    - Transfer, A - Dz (Box 36:, Folder 801)
    - Transfer, Ea - Haz (Box 37:, Folder 802)
    - Transfer, Lam - Q (Box 38:, Folder 803)
    - Transfer, Ra - XYZ (Box 39:, Folder 804)
    - Private transfer, 1901-1925 (Box 40:, Folder 805)
    - Private transfer, 1916-1927 (Box 40:, Folder 806)
    - Sales, A - L (Box 41:, Folder 807)
    - Sales, M - Z (Box 42:, Folder 808)
    - Sales, 1927-1929 (Box 43:, Folder 809)
    - General transfer, 1920-1934 (Box 43:, Folder 810)
    - General transfer, book 1 and 2 (Box 44:, Folder 811)
    - General transfer, book 3 (Box 45:, Folder 812)
    - General transfer, book 3A and 4 (Box 46:, Folder 813)
    - General transfer, book 5 and 6 (Box 47:, Folder 814)
  - Daybooks
    - Volume 1, 1848 June - 1849 July (Box 48:, Folder 815)
    - Volume 2, 1849 April - 1851 June (Box 49:, Folder 816)
    - Volume 3, 1850 August - 1854 June (Box 50:, Folder 817)
    - Volume 4, 1850 December - 1852 December (Box 51:, Folder 818)
    - Volume 5, 1853 January - 1855 December (Box 52:, Folder 819)
    - Volume 6, 1856 November - 1857 November (Box 53:, Folder 820)
    - Volume 7, 1856 July - 1857 August, 1863 September - 1865 March (Box 54:, Folder 821)
    - Volume 8 - F&B, 1858 June - 1859 October (Box 55:, Folder 822)
    - Volume 9 - daybook, 1858 August - 1859 December (Box 56:, Folder 823)
    - ledger, 1854 June - 1856 January (Box 56:, Folder 824)
    - Volume 10 - FF&M, 1861 July - 1863 August (Box 57:, Folder 825)
    - Volume 11, 1865 April - 1866 December (Box 58:, Folder 826)
    - Volume 12, 1879 October - 1880 October (Box 59:, Folder 827)
  - Cashbooks
    - Volume 1 - cashbook, 1853 January - 1856 October (Box 60:, Folder 828)
    - Daybook, 1860 January - 1861 June (Box 60:, Folder 829)
    - Volume 2, 1857 September - 1864 November (Box 61:, Folder 830)
    - Volume 1, 1866 March - 1871 October (Box 62:, Folder 831)
    - Volume 2, 1867 January - 1869 May (Box 63:, Folder 832)
    - Volume 3, 1871 November - 1879 June (Box 64:, Folder 833)
    - Volume 4, 1879 July - 1884 September (Box 65:, Folder 834)
    - Volume 5, 1884 September - 1887 December (Box 66:, Folder 835)
    - Volume 6, 1886 January - 1887 April (Box 67:, Folder 836)
    - Volume 7, 1888 January - 1890 July (Box 68:, Folder 837)
    - Volume 8, 1890 August - 1892 July (Box 69:, Folder 838)
    - Volume 9, 1892 August - 1892 December (Box 70:, Folder 839)
    - Volume 10, 1893 January - 1894 December (Box 71:, Folder 840)
    - Volume 11, 1895 January - 1896 November (Box 72:, Folder 841)
    - Volume 12, 1896 December - 1898 November (Box 73:, Folder 842)
    - Volume 13 “D”, 1898 November - 1900 May (Box 74:, Folder 843)
    - Volume 14 “E”, 1900 June - 1901 December (Box 75:, Folder 844)
    - Volume 15 “F”, 1902 January - 1903 April (Box 76:, Folder 845)
    - Volume 16 “G”, 1903 May - 1904 October (Box 77:, Folder 846)
    - Volume 17 “H”, 1904 November - 1906 March (Box 78:, Folder 847)
    - Volume 18 “I”, 1906 March 1907 April (Box 79:, Folder 848)
    - Volume 19 “J”, 1907 May - 1908 July (Box 80:, Folder 849)
    - Volume 20 “K”, 1908 August - 1909 December (Box 81:, Folder 850)
    - Volume 21 “L”, 1910 January - 1911 December (Box 82:, Folder 851)
    - Volume 22 “M”, 1912 January - 1913 December (Box 83:, Folder 852)
    - Volume 23 “N”, 1914 January - 1916 April (Box 84:, Folder 853)
    - Volume 24 “O”, 1916 May - 1918 May (Box 85:, Folder 854)
    - Volume 25 “P”, 1918 June - 1920 March (Box 86:, Folder 855)
    - Volume 26 “Q”, 1920 April - 1921 November (Box 87:, Folder 856)
    - Volume 27 “R”, 1921 December - 1923 October (Box 88:, Folder 857)
    - Volume 28 “S”, 1923 November - 1925 July (Box 89:, Folder 858)
    - Volume 29 “T”, 1925 August - 1926 December (Box 90:, Folder 859)
    - Volume 30 “U”, 1927 January - 1928 May (Box 91:, Folder 860)
    - Volume 31 “V”, 1928 June - 1929 August (Box 92:, Folder 861)
    - Volume 32 “W”, 1929 August - 1930 July (Box 93:, Folder 862)
    - Volume 33 “X”, 1930 August - 1931 December (Box 94:, Folder 863)
    - Volume 34 “Y”, 1932 January - 1933 December (Box 95:, Folder 864)
    - Volume 35 “Z”, 1934 January - 1935 June (Box 96:, Folder 865)
    - Volume 36 “F”, 1931 January - 1934 December (Box 97:, Folder 866)
  - Cash Received
    - Volume 1 “A”, 1935 (Box 98:, Folder 867)
    - Volume 2 “B”, 1940 (Box 99:, Folder 868)
    - Volume 3 “C”, 1943, 1944 (Box 100:, Folder 869)
    - Volume 4 “D”, 1947, 1948 (Box 101:, Folder 870)
    - Volume 5 “E”, 1950 (Box 102:, Folder 871)
    - Volume 6 “F”, 1953 (Box 103:, Folder 872)
    - Volume 7 “G”, 1955 (Box 104:, Folder 873)
    - Volume 8 “H”, 1957 (Box 105:, Folder 874)
    - Volume 9 “I”, 1959 (Box 106:, Folder 875)
  - Cash Disbursed
    - 1926 (Box 107:, Folder 876)
    - 1929 (Box 108:, Folder 877)
    - Volume 1 “A”, 1935 (Box 109:, Folder 878)
    - Volume 2 “B”, 1937 (Box 110:, Folder 879)
    - Volume 3 “C”, 1939 (Box 111:, Folder 880)
    - Volume 4 “D”, 1940 (Box 112:, Folder 881)
    - Volume 5 “E”, 1942 (Box 113:, Folder 882)
    - Volume 6 “F”, 1943 (Box 114:, Folder 883)
    - Volume 7 “G”, 1944 (Box 115:, Folder 884)
    - Volume 8 “H”, 1945 (Box 116:, Folder 885)
    - Volume 9 “I”, 1946 (Box 117:, Folder 886)
    - Volume 10 “J”, 1947 (Box 118:, Folder 887)
    - Volume 11 “K”, 1948 (Box 119:, Folder 888)
    - Volume 12 “L”, 1950 (Box 120:, Folder 889)
    - Volume 13 “M”, 1951 (Box 121:, Folder 890)
    - Volume 14 “N”, 1952 (Box 122:, Folder 891)
    - Volume 15 “O”, 1953 (Box 123:, Folder 892)
    - Volume 16 “P”, 1954 (Box 124:, Folder 893)
    - Volume 17 “Q”, 1955 (Box 125:, Folder 894)
    - Volume 18 “R”, 1956 (Box 126:, Folder 895)
  - Journals
    - Volume 1, 1853 January - 1856 February (Box 127:, Folder 896)
    - Volume 2, 1856 July - 1857 August (Box 128:, Folder 897)
    - Volume 1 “B”, 1868 January - 1870 August (Box 129:, Folder 898)
    - Volume 2 “C”, 1870 August - 1872 March (Box 130:, Folder 899)
    - Volume 3 “D”, 1872 October - 1874 November (Box 131:, Folder 900)
    - Volume 4 “E”, 1874 November - 1877 November (Box 132:, Folder 901)
    - Volume 5 “F”, 1877 November - 1880 September (Box 133:, Folder 902)
    - Volume 6 “G”, 1880 October - 1883 March (Box 134:, Folder 903)
    - Volume 7 “H”, 1883 March - 1885 March (Box 135:, Folder 904)
    - Volume 8 “I”, 1885 April - 1887 March (Box 136:, Folder 905)
    - Volume 9 “J”, 1887 April - 1889 February (Box 137:, Folder 906)
    - Volume 10 “K”, 1889 March - 1891 February (Box 138:, Folder 907)
    - Volume 11 “L”, 1891 March - 1892 December (Box 139:, Folder 908)
    - Volume 12 “M”, 1893 January - 1893 December (Box 140:, Folder 909)
    - Volume 13 “N”, 1894 January - 1895 June (Box 141:, Folder 910)
    - Volume 14 “O”, 1895 July - 1897 October (Box 142:, Folder 911)
    - Volume 15 “P”, 1897 November - 1900 January (Box 143:, Folder 912)
    - Volume 16 “Q”, 1900-1902 (Box 144:, Folder 913)
    - Volume 17 “R”, 1902-1904 (Box 145:, Folder 914)
    - Volume 18 “S”, 1904-1907 (Box 146:, Folder 915)
    - Volume 19 “T”, 1907-1908 (Box 147:, Folder 916)
    - Volume 20 “U”, 1909-1910 (Box 148:, Folder 917)
    - Volume 21 “V”, 1911 January - 1914 April (Box 149:, Folder 918)
    - Volume 22 “W”, 1914 July - 1916 September (Box 150:, Folder 919)
    - Volume 23 “Y”, 1922 January - 1926 November (Box 151:, Folder 920)
    - Volume 24 “Z”, 1926 December - 1929 December (Box 152:, Folder 921)
    - A, 1928 (Box 153:, Folder 922)
    - A1, 1930 (Box 154:, Folder 923)
    - A2, 1934 (Box 155:, Folder 924)
    - A3, 1939 (Box 156:, Folder 925)
    - A4, 1942 (Box 157:, Folder 926)
    - A5, 1946 (Box 158:, Folder 927)
    - A6, 1950 (Box 159:, Folder 928)
    - A7, 1954 (Box 160:, Folder 929)
    - A8, 1957 (Box 161:, Folder 930)
    - Journal “C”, 1889 March - 1891 March (Box 162:, Folder 931)
    - Journal, 1896 October - 1894 March (Box 163:, Folder 932)
    - Volume 1, 1896 October - 1898 December (Box 164:, Folder 933)
    - Volume 2, 1899 January - 1901 February (Box 165:, Folder 934)
    - Volume 3, 1901 March - 1903 April (Box 166:, Folder 935)
    - Volume 4, 1903 May - 1904 October (Box 167:, Folder 936)
    - Volume 5, 1904 November - 1906 February (Box 168:, Folder 937)
    - Volume 6, 1906 February - 1907 July (Box 169:, Folder 938)
    - Volume 7, 1907 July - 1908 December (Box 170:, Folder 939)
    - Volume 1, 1910 February - 1911 June (Box 171:, Folder 940)
    - Volume 2, 1911 July - 1912 October (Box 172:, Folder 941)
    - Volume 3, 1912 November - 1913 January (Box 173:, Folder 942)
    - Buffalo Volume 1 “A”, 1920 February - 1920 July (Box 174:, Folder 943)
    - Buffalo Volume 2 “B”, 1920 August - 1922 March (Box 175:, Folder 944)
    - Buffalo Volume 3 “C”, 1922 April - 1925 December (Box 176:, Folder 945)
    - Buffalo Volume 4 “D”, 1926 January - 1929 June (Box 177:, Folder 946)
    - Buffalo Volume 5 “E”, 1929 June - 1935 January (Box 178:, Folder 947)
    - 1916 October - 1921 December, (1 Volume) (Box 179:, Folder 948)
    - AIF Ledger, 1849 April - 1852 January (Box 180:, Folder 949)
    - Farrel Foundry ledger, 1850 December - 1852 July (Box 181:, Folder 950)
    - Journal, 1851 July - 1852 December (Box 181:, Folder 951)
    - Farrel Foundry (Box 181:, Folder 952)
    - Farrel and Johnson ledger, 1851 July - 1852 December (Box 182:, Folder 953)
    - Ledger, 1853 January - 1855 May (Box 183:, Folder 954)
    - Ledger, 1863 July - 1866 July (Box 183:, Folder 955)
    - Ledger, 1856 February - 1864 February (Box 184:, Folder 956)
    - Farrel and Johnson ledger, 1856 July - 1858 August (Box 185:, Folder 957)
    - F and B ledger, 1858 June - 1860 March (Box 186:, Folder 958)
    - A ledger, 1863 January - 1864 December (Box 187:, Folder 959)
    - Ledger, 1866 July - 1868 December (Box 188:, Folder 960)
    - Ledger, 1869 January - 1872 June (Box 189:, Folder 961)
    - D ledger and index, 1872 October - 1879 December (Box 190:, Folder 962)
    - E ledger and index, 1880 October - 1885 December (Box 191:, Folder 963)
    - F ledger, 1885-1896 (Box 192:, Folder 964)
    - H ledger, 1893-1894 (Box 193:, Folder 965)
    - I ledger, 1895-1896 (Box 194:, Folder 966)
    - J ledger, 1897-1898 (Box 195:, Folder 967)
    - K ledger, 1898-1900 (Box 196:, Folder 968)
    - Current Ledger, 1914-1942 (Box 197:, Folder 969)
    - Demand notes, 1896-1930 (Box 198:, Folder 970)
- Series V: Production Records, 1846-1948
  - Annual Inventory, 1906 (Box 199:, Folder 971-973)
  - Circulars, 1850-1866 (Box 199:, Folder 974)
  - Department expenses, 1915-1927 (Box 199:, Folder 975)
  - Department expenses, 1928-1933 (Box 199:, Folder 976)
  - Derby expenses, 1929-1931 (Box 199:, Folder 977)
  - Formula, 1891 (Box 199:, Folder 978)
  - Grinding wheel proposal, 1935 (Box 199:, Folder 979)
  - Gear list, 1883 (Box 199:, Folder 980)
  - Gear list, 1897 (Box 199:, Folder 981)
  - Gear list, 1918 (Box 199:, Folder 982)
  - Instruction book, crusher, 1905 (Box 199:, Folder 983)
  - Instruction book, gear sets, 1942 (Box 199:, Folder 984)
  - Instruction, H.D. roll grinders, 1948 (Box 199:, Folder 985)
  - Inventory, 1904-1909 (Box 199:, Folder 986)
  - Inventory - rolls, 1874 (Box 199:, Folder 987)
  - List of ordnance, 1865, 1867 (Box 199:, Folder 988)
  - Machine shop expenses, 1916-1918 (Box 199:, Folder 989)
  - Maintenance manual, U.S. Navy, ca. 1940s (Box 199:, Folder 990)
  - Nomenclature, 1927 (Box 199:, Folder 991)
  - Specifications - 19th century, 1846-1857 (Box 199:, Folder 992)
  - Specifications - Ansonia Water Canal, 1846 (Box 199:, Folder 993)
  - Specifications - Chicago Grain House, 1855 (Box 199:, Folder 994)
  - Specifications - Yankee Gang Mill, 1857 (Box 199:, Folder 995)
  - Proposal for covering motor and control specifications for heavy duty roll grinders, 1934 (Box 199:, Folder 996)
  - Heavy duty roll grinder parts list specifications, 1928-1929 (Box 199:, Folder 997)
- Series VI: Labor Records, 1848-1956
  - Office book, 1907-1916 (Box 200:, Folder 998)
  - Office pay, 1903-1907 (Box 200:, Folder 999)
  - Payroll, 1848 August - 1954 July (Box 200:, Folder 1000)
  - Rollroom piece work, 1899 January - 1900 December (Box 200:, Folder 1001)
  - Salary records - “black book”, ca. 1940s (Box 200:, Folder 1002-1017)
  - Statistics - operating machine hours, 1915-1916 (1924) (Box 200:, Folder 1018)
  - Time book, 1958-1859 (Box 200:, Folder 1019)
  - Payroll, 1916 January - 1928 September (Box 201:, Folder 1020)
  - Payroll, 1928 September - 1938 April (Box 201:, Folder 1021)
  - Payroll, 1938 April - 1943 May (Box 201:, Folder 1022)
  - Payroll, 1943 May - 1945 May (Box 201:, Folder 1023)
  - Payroll, 1945 May - 1946 October (Box 201:, Folder 1024)
  - Payroll, 1946 October - 1948 March (Box 201:, Folder 1025)
  - Payroll, 1948 March - 1949 August (Box 202:, Folder 1026)
  - Payroll, 1949 August - 1951 January (Box 202:, Folder 1027)
  - Payroll, 1951 January - 1952 June (Box 202:, Folder 1028)
  - Payroll, 1952 June - 1953 November (Box 202:, Folder 1029)
  - Payroll, 1953 November - 1955 May (Box 202:, Folder 1030)
  - Payroll, 1955 May - 1956 May (Box 202:, Folder 1031)
  - Record of employees, 1897-1908 (Box 203:, Folder 1032)
  - Time book and payroll, 1867 November - 1871 July (Box 204:, Folder 1033)
  - Time book and payroll, 1871 August - 1877 July (Box 205:, Folder 1034)
  - Time book and payroll, 1898 November - 1901 January (Box 206:, Folder 1035)
  - Time book and payroll, 1918 March - 1920 January (Box 207:, Folder 1036)
  - Wage records, 1934-1947 (Box 208:, Folder 1037)
  - Wage records, 1948-1952 (Box 209:, Folder 1038)
  - Weekly salaries, 1954; (1 Volume) (Box 210:, Folder 1039)
- Series VII: Birmingham Iron Foundry, 1850-1929
  - Subseries A: Administrative Records
    - General subject
      - Building records, 1906-1925 (Box 211:, Folder 1040)
      - Collins Co. orders, 1891 (Box 211:, Folder 1041)
      - Company owned stocks, 1858-1890 (Box 211:, Folder 1042)
      - E.W. Bliss Co. patent inquiry, 1925-1926 (Box 211:, Folder 1043-1044)
      - Farrel Co. merger, 1927 (Box 211:, Folder 1045-1047)
      - Group insurance, 1924 (Box 211:, Folder 1048)
      - Miner and Peck division, 1919-1920 (Box 211:, Folder 1049)
      - N.Y. legislation, 1897-1899 (Box 211:, Folder 1050)
      - Shelton Foundry, 1896 (Box 211:, Folder 1051)
    - Legal
      - Articles of incorporation, 1850 (Box 211:, Folder 1052)
      - Contracts and agreements, 1897-1911 (Box 211:, Folder 1053)
      - Deeds, 1850-1851 (1860) (Box 211:, Folder 1054)
      - Promissory notes, 1860-1900 (Box 211:, Folder 1055)
      - Protest notes, 1858-1900 (Box 211:, Folder 1056)
    - Stocks
      - Certificate of increase of capital stock, 1895 (Box 211:, Folder 1057)
      - Certificates (see also Volumes, end of series), 1850-1907 (Box 211:, Folder 1058)
      - Dividend accounts (see Volumes, end of series)
      - Proxy votes, 1927 (Box 211:, Folder 1059)
      - Stockholders of record, (1910) 1917-1927 (Box 211:, Folder 1060)
      - Transfer book, 1850-1889 (Box 211:, Folder 1061)
      - Transfer book, 1894-1917 (Box 211:, Folder 1062)
    - General administrative
      - Appraisal, No. 1, 1909 (Box 211:, Folder 1063-1066)
      - Appraisal, No. 2, 1909 (Box 211:, Folder 1067-1070)
      - Cost analysis statistics, 1918-1924 (Box 211:, Folder 1071)
      - Cost book, 1894-1896 (Box 211:, Folder 1072)
      - Cost book, 1896-1897 (Box 212:, Folder 1073)
      - Cost sheets, 1896 (Box 212:, Folder 1074)
      - Inventory, 1884 (Box 212:, Folder 1075)
      - Inventory - insurance, 1901 (Box 212:, Folder 1076-1079)
      - Machinery price book, 1905 (Box 212:, Folder 1080)
      - Memorandum, 1902-1916 (Box 212:, Folder 1081)
  - Subseries B: Production Records, 1899-1928
    - Gear list, 1899 (Box 212:, Folder 1082)
    - Gear list, 1918 (Box 212:, Folder 1083)
    - Inventory - machine ship, 1928 (Box 212:, Folder 1084)
    - Specifications - bldg. repairs, 1909 (Box 212:, Folder 1085)
    - Specifications - foundation, 1906 (Box 212:, Folder 1086)
  - Subseries C: Sales Records
    - Catalogs (Box 212:, Folder 1087-1095)
    - Order books, 1863-1867 (Box 213:, Folder 1096)
    - Order books, 1863-1873 (Box 213:, Folder 1097)
    - Order books, 1865-1870 (Box 213:, Folder 1098)
    - Order books, 1873-1891 (Box 213:, Folder 1099)
    - Order books, 1884-1890 (Box 213:, Folder 1100)
    - Order books, 1906-1917 (Box 213:, Folder 1101)
    - Order Card, 1891 (Box 213:, Folder 1102)
  - Subseries D: General Accounts
    - Balance sheets, 1900-1927 (Box 213:, Folder 1103)
    - Bills and receipts, 1871-1877 (Box 213:, Folder 1104)
    - Cash book
      Scope and Contents note
      (see Volumes, end of series)
    - Journals, (2 volumes)
    - Ledger, (3 volumes)
    - Cash book, 1927-1929 (Box 214:, Folder 1105)
    - Certificates, 1895-1907 (Box 215:, Folder 1106)
    - Dividend accounts, 1894-1924 (Box 216:, Folder 1107)
    - Journal, 1925-1928 (Box 217:, Folder 1108)
    - Journal C, 1886-1892 (Box 218:, Folder 1109)
    - Ledger A, 1864-1875 (Box 219:, Folder 1110)
    - Ledger G, 1926-1927 (Box 220:, Folder 1111)
    - Ledger - Akron branch, 1916-1925 (Box 221:, Folder 1112)
- Series VIII: Newsclippings and Publications, 1909-1978
  - Articles by employees (Box 222:, Folder 1113)
  - Articles by Franklin Farrel, 3rd, 1961 (Box 222:, Folder 1114)
  - J.R. Bowen's file, 1909-1950 (Box 222:, Folder 1115-1116)
  - Company activities (Box 222:, Folder 1117-1127)
  - Company buildings and land (Box 222:, Folder 1128-1119)
  - In house publications (Box 222:, Folder 1130-1132)
  - In house publications
    - 75th anniversary, 1923 (Box 222:, Folder 1133)
    - Cuban exposition, 1925 (Box 222:, Folder 1134)
    - Emhart publications (Box 222:, Folder 1135)
    - Farrel Co. centennial, 1948 (Box 222:, Folder 1136)
    - F-B Newsletter, 1942-1945 (Box 222:, Folder 1137-1138)
    - F-B Notes (1 Volume), 1940-1943 (Box 222:, Folder 1139)
  - Personnel (Box 222:, Folder 1140-1142)
  - Publicity, 1978 (Box 222:, Folder 1143)
  - Town activities (Box 222:, Folder 1144-1146)
- Series IX: Audio Visual Records, 1850-1968
  - Subseries A: Photographs
    - Rolling mills, ca. 1930s (Box 223:, Folder 1147-1148)
    - Rod mills, ca. 1940-1955 (Box 223:, Folder 1149)
    - Stone ore and crushing machinery, ca. 1930-1949 (Box 223:, Folder 1150)
    - Beaux Bridge Sugar Factory, ca. 1930s (Box 223:, Folder 1151)
    - St. Mary Sugar Cooperative, ca. 1940s (Box 223:, Folder 1152)
    - St. James Sugar Cooperative, ca. 1940s (Box 224:, Folder 1153)
    - St. James Sugar Cooperative, ca. 1940s (Box 224:, Folder 1154)
    - Events (Box 224:, Folder 1155-1156)
    - Buildings (Box 224:, Folder 1157)
    - Facilities (Box 224:, Folder 1158-1172)
    - Facilities scrapbook (Box 224:, Folder 1173)
    - Personal - Farrel Family (Box 224:, Folder 1174)
    - Personnel (Box 224:, Folder 1175-1178)
    - Products and machinery (Box 224A:, Folder 1179-1190)
    - Sugar mills - Argentina, 1960-1964 (Box 224A:, Folder 1191)
    - Sugar mills - Bryant Sugar (Box 224A:, Folder 1192)
    - Sugar mills - Cuba Sugar Mill (Box 224A:, Folder 1193)
    - Sugar mills - Dominican, 1955-1957 (Box 224A:, Folder 1194)
    - Sugar mills - Louisiana, St. Mary's, 1947 (Box 224A:, Folder 1195)
    - Sugar mills - Mexico, San Cristobal, 1947-1958 (Box 224A:, Folder 1196)
    - Sugar mills - St. James (Box 224A:, Folder 1197)
    - WWII activities (see also Series IX) (Box 224A:, Folder 1198-1199)
  - Subseries B: Audiotapes, 14 audiotapes
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Use of audiotapes requires production of listening copies.
    - Annual meeting, 1957 March 21 (Box 225:, Folder 1200)
    - Annual meeting, 1958 March 20 (Box 225:, Folder 1201)
    - Annual meeting, 1959 March 19 (Box 225:, Folder 1202)
    - Annual meeting, 1960 March 17 (Box 225:, Folder 1203)
    - Annual meeting, 1961 March (Box 225:, Folder 1204)
    - Annual meeting, 1962 March 15 (Box 225:, Folder 1205)
    - Annual meeting, 1963 March 21 (Box 225:, Folder 1206)
    - Annual meeting, 1964 (Box 225:, Folder 1207)
    - Annual meeting, 1965 (Box 225:, Folder 1208)
    - Annual meeting, 1966 March 17 (Box 225:, Folder 1209)
    - Annual meeting, 1967 March 16 (Box 225:, Folder 1210)
    - Annual meeting, 1968 March 21 (Box 225:, Folder 1211)
    - Conversation between Fernley Banbury and Arthur Strahan, 1959 (Disk Dodd CD 299, Box 225:, Reel 1989-0053/RR1a-b)
      Use of audiotapes requires production of listening copies. Use Dodd CD 299.
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
      1 channel, half track, 3 3/4 ips
    - Special stockholders' meeting, 1968 (Box 225:, Folder 1213)
  - Subseries C: Memorabilia, undated, 1884-
    - Embossers - BIF and Farrel Corp. (Box 226:, Folder 1214)
    - Stamps (Box 226:, Folder 1215)
    - Anniversary seals, 1948 (Box 226:, Folder 1216)
    - Badges - special state police (Box 226:, Folder 1217)
    - Pins - safety commission (Box 226:, Folder 1218)
    - Paperweight - Southern Exposition, 1884 (Box 226:, Folder 1219)
    - Commemorative service pins and tietacks (Box 226:, Folder 1220)
    - Business cards (Box 226:, Folder 1221)
    - Certificate of apprenticeship (Box 226:, Folder 1222)
    - Date book, 1921 (Box 226:, Folder 1223)
    - Embossed seals (Box 226:, Folder 1224)
    - Foundry Education Foundation Certificate, 1954 (Box 226:, Folder 1225)
    - Letterhead samples (Box 226:, Folder 1226)
    - Navy “E” award, 1942 (Box 226:, Folder 1227)
  - Subseries D: Plans and Blueprints
    - Buffalo operations
      - Land survey, Tonawanda, NY, 1942 (Box 226:, Folder 1228)
      - NY Central Railroad tracks used by Farrel Co. 1921 and revisions (Box 226:, Folder 1229-1230)
      - Victory plant, Tonawanda, NY (Box 226:, Folder 1231-1232)
    - Facilities
      - Farrel Foundry and Machine Co., 1897 (Box 226:, Folder 1233)